I want to show you an improv demonstration I call "Yes or".
This is a demonstration in the bad stuff, because really what we want to do in general is we want to "yes and."
We want to listen to each other’s ideas and support them, but it's useful to demonstrate what happens when we don't do that when we do something else like for example "yes or."
So, what Shannon and I are going to do is we are going to have a little conversation where we're planning something; maybe we're planning my birthday party.
Every line we say is going to start, except for the first one is going to start with "yes or."
So, I am going to say let's plan my birthday party and Shannon's going to say yes or blah, blah, blah, blah and then I'm going to say yes or blah, blah, blah, blah back and forth until the scene kind of comes to an end.
So, here we go. "Let's plan my birthday party." "Yes or we could go get your car washed." "Yes or we could go shopping for my birthday presents.”Yes or we could go see a movie this afternoon."
"Yes or we could go out to eat".
"Yes or we could go take that big paddle boat on the river."
"Yes or we could sky dive."
"Yes or we could go spelunking."
"Yes or we could eat bats."
“Yes or we could drive a bus."
Alright good excellent, so that's a little bit of "yes or."
You can see really quickly what happens to the conversation.
First of all what happened to my birthday party?
It probably looks like it isn't going to happen.
So, what we do is we leave; I keep leaving ideas behind.
You go oh we can do this or that or the other or the other and we don't actually move in any specific direction.
I'm sure a lot of you guys have had conversations like that I find a lot of conversations about where to go eat dinner sound a lot like that, a lot of business meetings where you're brainstorming or having ideas sound like that.
It can be pretty unproductive because you don't seem to be getting anywhere with your conversation.
So, instead of "yes or "what we want to do is we want to do "yes and,” but this demonstration gets you an idea for what happens when you have these "yes, or" conversations.
So, this is a little "yes, or" demonstration.